<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-07T10:33:21-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Virginia Tech Digital Libraries Platform</title><subtitle>VTDLP is a cloud-native, digital libraries solution supporting preservation and acces taking advantage of the efficiencies of Amazon Web Services. It is a collectio of CloudFormation templates, code implementing microservices to support digital library functions, and web applications supporting providing user access.</subtitle><author><name>VTDLP</name></author><entry><title type="html">Multi Site Achieved</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Multi-Site-Achieved/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Multi Site Achieved" /><published>2020-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Multi-Site-Achieved</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Multi-Site-Achieved/">&lt;p&gt;The Digital Libraries Team has achieved multi-site status!  Our current sprint delivers a Minimum Viable Product for Southwest Virginia Archive and begins work on a VT Publishing Podcast Library.  The SWVA site will replace the existing &lt;a href=&quot;http://di.lib.vt.edu/&quot; title=&quot;Omeka site&quot;&gt;Omeka site&lt;/a&gt;, which is our second legacy system retirement!  Here’s to reducing maintanence obligations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features of the Podcast Library include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to and preservation of the transcripts, files, and metadata&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RSS aggerator support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audio streaming and direct download&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;View and download analytics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User submission interface&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support for user-provided transcripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is pretty exciting for us since it’s the first non-static image collection we’re implementing in the DLP.  It also provides functionality that we can use to support oral history collections, of which the Libraries has many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a future iteration, we’d like to add time-range URI linking and automated transcription generation when one is not provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also working on a new template painstakingly arrived at in close cooperation between our Web Development Librarian, Web Designer, and stakeholders.  April’s going to be a big month for the team!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>VTDLP</name></author><summary type="html">The Digital Libraries Team has achieved multi-site status! Our current sprint delivers a Minimum Viable Product for Southwest Virginia Archive and begins work on a VT Publishing Podcast Library. The SWVA site will replace the existing Omeka site, which is our second legacy system retirement! Here’s to reducing maintanence obligations.</summary></entry></feed>